ideapaint.com 2014-06-06

# Privacy Policy | IdeaPaint™

IdeaPaint, Inc. is dedicated to the privacy and rights of our customers. We do not sell or distribute any of the information collected from patrons of our products or services for profit or any other reason. For a detailed description of our practices, read our privacy policy below.

You can contact IdeaPaint by calling 800.393.5250 or emailing [info@ideapaint.com](mailto:info@ideapaint.com).

IdeaPaint Physical Address:

290 Eliot Street  
2nd Floor Ashland, MA 01721

IdeaPaint collects and stores information about its customers including, but not limited to: email address, survey results, phone number, credit card number, and billing address. This information is for the sole use of IdeaPaint and used for billing accounts, new product and service notification, and customer support. IdeaPaint does not sell email lists, survey results, or any other customer information and is committed to keeping your information confidential. If you receive email through the IdeaPaint system and wish to opt-out, simply click the “Unsubscribe” link in the footer of the email. To be completely removed from the list that you are a part of, please contact the sender of the email by replying to that email (IdeaPaint may not be the list origin). If you receive an email directly from IdeaPaint and wish to have your name removed from our list, please reply to us at info@ideapaint.com with your request and we will be happy to honor it.

Personally identifiable information can be disclosed to government agencies subject to warrants, subpoenas, and other governmental orders. In addition, personally identifiable information submitted by you in public forums on this site and via email campaign (view as a web page link) will be visible and displayed publicly.

IdeaPaint does not intentionally collect information from anyone under the age of 13.

In the case of a merger or bankruptcy, IdeaPaint will not sell customer information to 3rd parties. The data would either become a part of the merger (keeping privacy intact) or would be destroyed.

IdeaPaint keeps customer information for at least the duration that the account is active (paying). Currently, IdeaPaint archives all data which is then stored in a secure location.

In accordance with our commitment to protect personal privacy, IdeaPaint adheres to the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Privacy Principles as developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce in consultation with the European Commission, as well as the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Privacy Principles as developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce in consultation with the Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner of Switzerland. The U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks comprise seven privacy principles and fifteen Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs) that are referred to in this policy. These principles and FAQs may be found at: <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

IdeaPaint does not install cookies, or any other software on your computer. When an email is sent to a recipient through the IdeaPaint service, open and click information is gathered and reported back to the IdeaPaint account owner for the purposes of tracking delivery and interest level. The IdeaPaint website uses analytics software to monitor traffic, but not personally identifiable information.

If a situation arises where you have a privacy dispute, please contact IdeaPaint directly and we will be happy to work with you in a fair and practical manner (see IdeaPaint contact information at the top of this page). If after speaking with IdeaPaint, you feel that you have not come to a mutually agreeable resolution, we shall participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the US data protection authorities to resolve disputes pursuant to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles.

IdeaPaint does not store credit card information submitted through our online payment system. IdeaPaint uses established payment gateways to process credit cards to ensure PCI compliance and security.

IdeaPaint customers set up a user profile within their account for the purpose of identifying them as the sender of email within the footer of the email. This is done to ensure compliance with the U.S. CAN-SPAM law. User profiles can be updated at any time by logging in to your account and clicking the My Account button in the top navigation on [www.ideapaint.com](http://www.ideapaint.com/).

IdeaPaint is dedicated to keeping your information secure. Each customer account is password-protected to ensure that only you have access to your information. IdeaPaint will never contact you with unsolicited phone calls or emails asking for your password so do not divulge your contact information to anyone contacting you in this manner. While we do everything in our power to ensure your information is secure, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed 100% safe from those wishing to unlawfully obtain it.

Questions relating to this policy can be sent to [info@ideapaint.com](mailto:info@ideapaint.com) or you can call 800.393.5250.

The current privacy policy is effective May 15, 2012.

On December 16, 2003, President Bush signed into law the Controlling the Assault of Non-Solicited Pornography and Marketing Act of 2003 (CAN-SPAM Act), which establishes a framework for reducing unsolicited email. The law prohibits predatory and abusive commercial email practices. IdeaPaint fully complies with and adheres to the CAN-SPAM Act.

Email is an extremely important and effective means of communication and is used by millions of Americans on a daily basis for personal and commercial purposes. Its convenience and efficiency, however, are increasingly threatened by the rise in spam. Spam currently accounts for over half of all email traffic. Today, most spam is fraudulent or deceptive in nature. The growth in spam also imposes significant costs on Internet Service Providers (ISPs), businesses, and other organizations, since they can only handle a finite volume of email without making further investments in their infrastructure.
